Jose Ramon Alonso Tapia **CURRICULUM**

SUMMARY

Degree in Electronics, but always worked as a Software Engineer, both in

Spain and in England.

Main experience is in C, Linux, Java and scripting languages.

Currently learning web technologies (HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Nodejs,

Angular, Django and more) in order to become a competent full-stack

web developer.

As a long time Linux user, I am a frequent self-learner and a very

inquisitive person. I self taught GNU/Linux, as well as Perl and regular

expressions.

NOTE: I have the Certificate of Disability

Contact Details

Email ----> jose.alonso.programmer@gmail.com

My CV online ----> https://josealonso.github.io/

LinkedIn ----> https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseramonalonsotapia/

Github -----> https://github.com/josealonso

EDUCATION

2017 - 2018 Web Startup Engineering Bootcamp in KeepCoding

- * Git and GitHub
- * Front-end Development: HTML5, CSS3 and **JavaScript**. Ajax, Grunt/Gulp, SASS, RWD.
- * Advanced Backend Development with **Node.js** and with Python/Django.
- * DevOps with Node.js.
- * Angular 4.
- * Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch. Microservicies with Docker.
- * UX + IA. SEO + Google Analytics + Social Media SCRUM and Agile methodologies.
- * Web Components and Polymer. Frameworks: ReactJS, Electron, Ionic.

2004 - 2008 Studies of Engineer in Electronics

University of Alcala, Madrid, Spain.

- Operating Systems, Real-Time Systems and Ada language, The Linux Kernel.
- Theory of microprocessors, types of caches.
- Communications.
- Computer Networks (TCP/IP), Control Systems, Semiconductor Devices, Heavy Mathematics.

2003 Studies in the University of Alabama, United States

Exchange student, thanks to a scholarship granted by my university in Spain.

Some courses on Computer Science and Electronics.

2001 Erasmus Student in Sweden

Final Degree Project: Programming in assembly language an application for the Microchip PIC16F84 microcontroller.

1996 - 2001 Engineering in Industrial Electronics

University of Alcala, Madrid, Spain.

• Bachelor's degree in Electronics.

EMPLOYMENT

Embedded Software Engineer

Jan 2015 - Oct 2016

LEAR at Tarragona, Spain.

Embedded Software Engineer for automotive systems. C Programmer and System Validation Engineer.

Embedded Software Engineer Jun 2014 – Sept 2015

KBioSystems Ltd. at Basildon, United Kingdom. Automation sector.

Programming in C the ARM Cortex-M microcontroller, using an Eclipsebased IDE. Also programming a tactile display that communicates with the mentioned microcontroller.

Topics: interaction between hardware and software, driving **stepper and DC motors**, using the **RS232** and the **CAN** communication protocols.

Software Engineer

Jun 2013 - Jan 2014

Glasswall Solutions at Chelmsford, United Kingdom.

Programming in a C-based, non-procedural language.

I occasionally used **Perl** and **Python**. I mentored some placement students.

Java Programmer

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012

Personal project. Java Swing application to generate Latex-based curricula.

I learned **Latex**, bibtex, Java programming and how an event-driven graphical application works.

Work in Madrid, Spain

2007 - 2010

Main duties: Linux administrator and programmer in C/C++.

Technologies: gcc toolchain, scripting in Linux and in Windows, **Java**, databases, Version Control Systems.